A Guide to the Records of the Secretary of Transportation, 2006-2010
Library of Virginia
- Series V. Projects & Studies, 2000-2006., Extent: 8 boxes. (Box 1-8)
  - Subseries C: Department of Rail & Public Transportation (DRPT), 2002-2006., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
    The Department of Rail & Public Transportation subseries is housed in one archival box and is arranged in alphabetical order. This subseries contains correspondence, memorandums, reports, and other items mainly related to the Dulles Rail Corridor and the Governor's Commission for Rail Enhancement in the 21st Century.
    - Agency Hiring Requests, 2002-2005. (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Dulles Rail Corridor, 2003-2004. (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Governor's Commission for Rail Enhancement in the 21st Century, 2004. (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - High Bridge Trail State Park, 2004-2005. (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Richmond to D.C. Rail Corridor, 2004. (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Subseries D: Highways, 2002-2006., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
    The Highways subseries is housed in one archival box and is arranged in alphabetical order. This subseries includes correspondence, minutes, reports, and presentations regarding Interstate 81 and Routes 25, 29, and 58.
    - Interstate 81, 2003-2006. (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Route 28 Corridor Improvements, 2003-2005. (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Route 29
      - Hydraulic Road, 2004. (Box 86, Folder 8)
      - Summit, 2004. (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Route 58, 2002-2003. (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Subseries E: Virginia Department of Transportation (VDOT), 2000-2005., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 1-4)
    The Virginia Department of Transportation subseries is housed in four archival boxes and is arranged in alphabetical order. This subseries contains correspondence, agency hiring requests, and presentations. Some of the issues in this subseries include Amber Alerts, the Clarkton Bridge, the Joint Legislative Review & Audit Commission, the Report on the Alleged Discriminatory Practices in VDOT's Hampton Roads District, and VTrans2025.
    - Agency Hiring Requests
      - 2002-2003 (Box 86, Folder 11)
      - 2003 (Box 86, Folder 12)
      - 2003-2004 (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - 2004 (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - 2004 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Amber Alert Procedures, 2005. (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Attorney General's Office, 2002. (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Base Realignment and Closure (BRAC), 2005. (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Bicycle/Pedestrian Policy, 2003-2005. (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Bond Issues, 2002. (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Budget, 2002-2003. (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Clarkton Bridge
      - 2003-2004 (Box 87, Folder 10)
      - 2004 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Clean Air, 2003-2005. (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Hampton Roads Bridge Tunnel, 2005. (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - HOV Enforcement Task Force, 2003-2005. (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Highway Safety Corridor Program, 2004. (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Integrated Directional Signage Program (ISDP), 2004. (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Joint Legislative Review & Audit Commission (JLARC)
      - 2001 (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - 2003 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Lake Merriweather, 2003. (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Litter Control Task Force, 2004-2005. (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Multimodal Transportation Planning Office, 2005. (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Public-Private Transportation Act, 2002-2005. (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Pulaski County Bridge, 2003. (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Railroad Museum of Virginia, 2005. (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Reauthorization, 2002. (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - Report on the Alleged Discriminatory Practices in VDOT's Hampton Roads District
      - Part 1, 2005. (Box 88, Folder 15)
      - Part 2, 2005. (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - Rest Areas/Welcome Centers, 2002-2004. (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - Safety Service Patrol, 2002. (Box 88, Folder 18)
    - Six-Year Improvement Plan, 2002. (Box 88, Folder 19)
    - Springfield Interchange Bridge, 2004. (Box 88, Folder 20)
    - Statewide Cycling Accommodation Map, 2005. (Box 88, Folder 21)
    - Steel Plates (HB 408), 2004. (Box 88, Folder 22)
    - Telegraph Road Landslide, 2003-2004. (Box 88, Folder 23)
    - Transportation Enhancement Program, 2001-2003. (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Navy Right-of-Way Issues, 2004. (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - VTrans2025
      - 2002 (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - 2002-2004 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Waterway Signage, 2005. (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Woodrow Wilson Bridge, 2000-2004. (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Subseries F: Virginia Port Authority (VPA), 2001-2005., 2 boxes (Box 1-2)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - 2003 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - 2004 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - 2005 (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Agency Hiring Requests, 2002. (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - Craney Island, 2004. (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - Export Strategy, 2004. (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Maersk, 2001-2004. (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Norfolk Cruise Terminal Proposal, 2003. (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk Harbor Dredging, 2002-2003. (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Petersburg Intermodal Yard, 2003. (Box 91, Folder 3)
- Series VI: Public Relations, Activities, & Visits, 2002-2005., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  The Public Relations, Activities, & Visits series is housed in one archival box and is arranged in alphabetical order. The series contains speeches, articles, presentations, and photographs related to public relations' activities of Whittington Clement as Secretary of Transportation.
  This series mostly contains drafts of speeches or public comments made by Secretary Clement at various public appearances such as the Hampton Roads Maritime Association Meeting, the Ninth Annual Intelligent Transportation Society of Virginia Conference & Exhibition Dinner, the Annual BikeWalk Virginia Conference, and the VTA Annual Meeting. Also included in this series are articles written by Whittington Clement for the "Commentary II" section of the Richmond Times-Dispatch. Clement writes concerning various transportation issues including VDOT, public transit, DMV, and the Virginia Capital Trail. Lastly, this series contains publicity photographs of Whittington Clement & Governor Warner. Included are photographs from the Virginia Transit Association Meeting in 2002 and the Virginia Travel & Governor's Tourism Conference of 2004.
  - Photographs, 2002-2004. (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Richmond Times-Dispatch Articles, 2002-2005. (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Speech Material & Speeches
    - 2002 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - 2003 Jan.-May (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - 2003 June-2004 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Undated (Box 91, Folder 9)